<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
<title>Words About Songs</title>
<description>The latest content from Words About Songs.com</description>
<link>http://www.wordsaboutsongs.com</link>
<atom:link href="http://www.wordsaboutsongs.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
<language>en-us</language>
<managingEditor>herb@wordsaboutsongs.com (Herb Bowie)</managingEditor>
<webMaster>herb@wordsaboutsongs.com (Herb Bowie)</webMaster>
<lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2019 00:00 PDT</lastBuildDate>
<pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2019 00:00 PDT</pubDate>
<ttl>1440</ttl>
<item>
<title>Fruitcakes</title>
<link>http://www.wordsaboutsongs.com/index.html#fruitcakes</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.wordsaboutsongs.com/fruitcakes.html</guid>
<pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2018 00:00 PDT</pubDate>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;I’ve always considered this to be Jimmy Buffet’s masterwork. The musical backing is infectious, swaying and danceable, and the background vocals add depth. The words are cleverly crafted, and perfectly suited to Buffett’s conversational, wisecracking delivery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Author: Herb Bowie &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Village Green Preservation Society</title>
<link>http://www.wordsaboutsongs.com/index.html#the-village-green-preservation-society</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.wordsaboutsongs.com/the-village-green-preservation-society.html</guid>
<pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 00:00 PDT</pubDate>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;This is a rather amazing song by The Kinks, first released in 1968. I loved this song from the moment I first heard it, but my appreciation for it has only grown over the years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Author: Herb Bowie &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Will the Circle be Unbroken</title>
<link>http://www.wordsaboutsongs.com/index.html#will-the-circle-be-unbroken</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.wordsaboutsongs.com/will-the-circle-be-unbroken.html</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2018 00:00 PDT</pubDate>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;It’s certainly fair to categorize this song as a religious one, and more particularly as a Christian song, and yet, even though I consider myself to be a non-believer, my lack of faith doesn’t diminish my appreciation for this song in the slightest: if anything, I think it increases it. For unlike many songs that we could put in this category, this song does not seek to proselytize, or ask us to accept any particular religious teaching.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Author: Herb Bowie &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Don&apos;t Let Nobody Turn You Around</title>
<link>http://www.wordsaboutsongs.com/index.html#dont-let-nobody-turn-you-around</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.wordsaboutsongs.com/dont-let-nobody-turn-you-around.html</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2018 00:00 PST</pubDate>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;In this next series of songs, I’m going to highlight some that provide hope and strength in the face of societal adversity. (I might tag these with the theme of “resistance” if that hadn’t become such an overused term lately.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve always found this song from the Steve Miller Band to be uplifting and inspiring. The lyrics are pretty simple, but their effect is amplified by their musical delivery. And even though the whole track clocks in at under two -and-a-half minutes, there’s a lot going on here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Author: Herb Bowie &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Santa Claus is Comin&apos; to Town</title>
<link>http://www.wordsaboutsongs.com/index.html#santa-claus-is-comin-to-town</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.wordsaboutsongs.com/santa-claus-is-comin-to-town.html</guid>
<pubDate>Sat, 23 Dec 2017 00:00 PST</pubDate>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;“Santa Claus is Comin’ to Town” was written in 1934, and was first sung on Eddie Cantor’s radio show in that same year. It became an instant hit, and it’s been a perennial holiday favorite ever since.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Author: Herb Bowie &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Christmas Song</title>
<link>http://www.wordsaboutsongs.com/index.html#the-christmas-song</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.wordsaboutsongs.com/the-christmas-song.html</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2017 00:00 PST</pubDate>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;It would be hard to leave this one off of any list of holiday tunes. First of all, as it’s named, this is “&lt;em&gt;The&lt;/em&gt; Christmas Song.” Second of all, everyone has recorded a version of it – I have thirty different renditions of it in my own personal collection. Third, there’s the classic story of the song’s composition….&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Author: Herb Bowie &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Boogie Woogie Santa Claus</title>
<link>http://www.wordsaboutsongs.com/index.html#boogie-woogie-santa-claus</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.wordsaboutsongs.com/boogie-woogie-santa-claus.html</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2017 00:00 PST</pubDate>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;R&amp;amp;B singer Mabel Scott recorded this little number in 1948, and it’s been making its way onto stylish Christmas compilations ever since. The song was written by Leon René, who also penned “When the Swallows Come Back to Capistrano” and “Rockin’ Robin”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Author: Herb Bowie &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Christmas Time&apos;s A-Coming</title>
<link>http://www.wordsaboutsongs.com/index.html#christmas-times-a-coming</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.wordsaboutsongs.com/christmas-times-a-coming.html</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2017 00:00 PST</pubDate>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;This is a bluegrass song written by Bell Labs engineer and bluegrass fiddler Benjamin “Tex” Logan, and first recorded by Bill Monroe in 1951.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Author: Herb Bowie &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Star of Wonder</title>
<link>http://www.wordsaboutsongs.com/index.html#star-of-wonder</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.wordsaboutsongs.com/star-of-wonder.html</guid>
<pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 00:00 PST</pubDate>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;This is a lovely little song, written by Terre Roche and recorded &lt;em&gt;a cappella&lt;/em&gt; by The Roches for their Christmas album, &lt;em&gt;We Three Kings&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Author: Herb Bowie &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>My Favorite Things</title>
<link>http://www.wordsaboutsongs.com/index.html#my-favorite-things</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.wordsaboutsongs.com/my-favorite-things.html</guid>
<pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2017 00:00 PST</pubDate>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;Some might protest that “My Favorite Things” is not, strictly speaking, a Christmas song. After all, there is no mention of Christmas, and that “holiday” word appears nowhere in the lyrics. However, those points notwithstanding, it has been included on many a Christmas album, and it’s easy to see why: with references to packages, sleigh bells, snowflakes and winters – as well as the overall theme of “my favorite things” – it’s easy to sneak it into any holiday playlist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Author: Herb Bowie &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
